# MARILIA GILP

INTERACTIVE MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER

## CONTACT

- 343 777 8289
- mariliagilp@gmail.com
- Ottawa, ON
- http://gilp0025.github.io

# SKILLS

- Graphic Design
- User-centered design
- UX/Ui
- Usability best practices
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Develop wireframes
- HTML, CSS and Bootstrap
- WordPress and Shopify
- InVision and Adobe XD
- Creating clickable prototypes

# **EDUCATION**

### Interactive Media Design | Diploma

Algonquin College 2019 – Current

# Art Direction and Creative Advertisement | Open Course

Miami Ad School 2016 – 2018

# Digital Communications and Multimedia Design | Bachelor

Anhanguera Educacional 2004 – 2007

# **PROFILE**

Interactive Multimedia Designer with 5 years of experience in the field of graphic design – having worked on an extensive range of projects in the areas of web design and advertisement. Organized, positive, creative, problem-solver, with a keen eye for detail, a strong technical ability adapted to fast-paced environments working as a team member or independently, and a boundless enthusiasm for everything related to design.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER**

CANOA DIGITAL | 2019 - PRESENT

- Work with a team of four to develop on a daily basis social media ads, online campaigns, and deliver design solutions for more than 3 clients
- Create a visual identity manual and ensured the brand's consistency across projects and different platforms
- Design, develop and deploy 8 WordPress website using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap 3 framework with user experience in mind

### PRODUCT DESIGNER

NERDSTORE | LOCATION | 2018

- Reviewed and analyzed industry trends to support the development of new products in collaboration with account, creative and studio teams
- Developed visual concepts for home products, collectibles, and clothing within the nerd and geek theme
- Created moodboard to set the tone of voice for illustrations, packaging and labels used by freelancers for more than 20 different products.

#### ART DIRECTOR

ISOBAR | 2017

- Provided visual identity to small and medium companies strengthening their online presence
- Helped to create unique cross-platform solutions using design thinking concepts to handle communications between customer and business companies
- Prepared layouts for email marketing, banners, social media posts, and promotional advertising for 4 accounts

# MARILIAGILP

INTERACTIVE MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER

### **AWARDS**

### Dean's Honours List of Outstanding Academic Achievement

Algonquin College Term 2, Year 1 - 2021

### Dean's Honours List of Outstanding Academic Achievement

Algonquin College Term 1, Year 1 - 2020

# WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

### CREATIVE DESIGNER

AGÊNCIA TUDO | 2015 - 2017

- Developed graphic and digital materials for 20 corporate events, fairs, conventions
- Created logos, graphic and digital materials and concepts for stands and kiosks, monitoring their effectiveness and people engagement in 20 events.
- Collaborated with external design team and internal staff to create and launch events with 250k people attending daily

## OTHER EXPERIENCES

#### STUDENT LEADERSHIP PROGRAM

ALGONQUIN COLLEGE | 2021

• Took part in a series of experiential workshops and leadership opportunities to explore and enhance leadership skills and help to gain the knowledge of how to lead on campus, career, and in the community

### LINKEDIN LEARNING CHAMPIONS

LINKEDIN | 2020 - 2021

 Started a project to show the fun part of studying, throughout photoshoots showing scenes and picturesque approaches from the educational environment

### TEAM LEADER AND USER INTERFACE DESIGNER

Adobe Creative Jam | 2019

 Gathered a team of four to create a full working prototype in less than 10 hours using the Adobe XD

### TEAM LEADER AND USER INTERFACE DESIGNER

Adobe Creative Jam | 2019

 Wrote 40 messages using different calligraphy styles to connect survivors of childhood cancer with children currently undergoing treatment in the Ottawa and Greater Toronto regions